# **Yoandy Vargas**

# **Front-End Developer**

321-900-3113
YOANDYVARGAS.COM
YOANDY.VARGAS@ICLOUD.COM

## **Summary**

Creative Front-End Developer with an eye for design and a passion for building and delivering pixel-perfect, robust, and accessible user interfaces. Experienced, diligent, and motivated recent graduate with a B.A. in Digital Media - Web Design and Development.

# **Experience**

#### Specialist @ Apple

Aug 2017 - Present | Orlando, FL

- o Install and maintain internal software on 200+ devices preserving device security, affording engaging customer demo experiences, and supporting day-to-day business-critical tools.
- OSupport and mentor up to 60 team members in troubleshooting complex system issues, navigating through challenging conversations, and sharing best practices to ensure the team is prepared to deliver timely resolutions.
- Facilitate and deliver pilot educational "How-To" sessions in English, Spanish, and Portuguese for groups of up to 15 people with 100% attendance and a 100% score in customer feedback surveys.
- ODeliver exceptional customer experiences empowering people with the tools and knowledge to do their life's best work. As a result, I average 20% higher than the store and market average in Net Promoter Score.

#### Web Designer & Developer Career Experience @ Apple

Jan 2021 - July 2021 | Remote

- Developed rebuilds of 6 legacy high-profile HTML templates for an internal email client using Kit, Stylus, Gulp, and Node. These templates account for 3500+ active users with 800,000+ quarterly recipients. One of the templates is a monthly newsletter that replaces manual work that took 2-4 days. This template achieves the same results in less than 30 minutes without developer resources.
- Researched and synthesized UX data to identify personas, discover use cases, and capture feedback by leading focus groups of 8 prousers. Using this data – I designed and prototyped the UI and other visual elements for 5 templates with Adobe Creative Suite.
- Established and implemented new team processes that modernized, organized, and improved efficiency. I migrated legacy templates to a new mono-repo that hosts the source and build files. The migration enabled archiving of 2 GitHub repositories with 153 stale and outdated branches. Additionally, I wrote an updated readme, Wiki, and a new developer onboarding document to reduce developer ramp-up time.

#### Front-End Developer Contract @ Callahan Genealogy (UCF)

Feb 2020 - Jan 2021 | Orlando, FL

- o Developed and deployed an interactive, modern, engaging, and flexible website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and WordPress that operates as a digital museum for a local historic African-American neighborhood.
- Optimized and improved website performance by as much as 78% on some pages by optimizing images, implementing lazy loading, removing unnecessary plugins, using Cloudflare CDN, and managing cache settings.
- Collaborated with the local neighborhood association and researched project needs and UX data to determine the best technical solution and information architecture of 200+ unique photographic stories.
- Lead technical knowledge transfer sessions with volunteers and provided a maintenance checklist, onboarding documents, readme, how-to video examples, and other technical documentation.

## **Education**

#### **University of Central Florida**

Orlando, FL - B.A. Digital Media - Web Design & Development, 2020

Languages

**Frameworks** 

**Tools & Platforms** 

HTML, CSS/Sass, JavaScript, Kit, Stylus, GraphQL

React, Gatsby

Git, GitHub, Gulp, Netlify, Adobe XD